moen.com 2019-12-09

# Moen Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Moen Incorporated understands the importance of privacy.  As a customer or visitor to our Moen website (“this Site”), we want you to know what information we learn about you when you visit this Site or otherwise interface with Moen through any medium including without limitation:

  * communication with Moen or its representatives orally (e.g., by phone), in writing (e.g., by email) or digitally (e.g., through this Site),
  * purchase, registration, returns or feedback you provide to Moen or its business partners for any Moen products,
  * interactions as part of any Moen contest or promotion,
  * se of Moen applications for mobile phones, tablets or other smart devices,
  * viewing Moen advertisements or promotional materials, or
  * interactions with or about Moen through social media whether through our websites or third party websites like Facebook, YouTube, Pinterest, Google+, Instagram and Twitter

(individually and collectively “Interfaces”). 

This Privacy Policy explains how we gather information and what we do with the information we learn passively as well as other information you actively provide us through this Site or any other Interface.  It also explains how you can view or change certain information we have about you. It does not apply to information you might provide on another site operated by one of our partners or affiliates or other companies selling our products. 

Our information collection efforts are designed to improve the shopping experience of our customers and to provide customers relevant information about our products, services, and promotions.  By accessing this Site or other Moen Interfaces, you are consenting to the gathering of your information as detailed in this Privacy Policy as updated from time to time.

#### Information Collected At This Site

There are two types of information that we can learn about you as you browse and use this Site or other Interfaces. Each type of information may be used under different circumstances.

  1. Anonymous Information that we gather passively from visitors to the Site and other Interfaces.  This information does not identify you specifically but tracks activities such as your age, gender, viewing, searching and purchasing history, general location, generic statistical and demographic information, and aggregated data and trends that we compile.
  2. Personal Information that you voluntarily provide which identifies you specifically including your name, address, email, phone number and credit card details. 

#### Anonymous Information (Gathered Passively)

We collect Anonymous Information from visitors to our Site and other Interfaces, including the referring URL, your IP address, which browser you used to come to the Site, the country, state or province, the pages of our Site or Interfaces that you viewed during your visit and any search terms entered on our Site, as well as other ways in which you digitally interact with Moen.  This information is used for various purposes including but not limited to improving and personalizing your shopping experience, improving our products, services and marketing, as well as improving this Site and other Interfaces, device applications, and system administration.  The information is also used to gather broad demographic information, and to monitor the level of activity on our Site or any Interface. We track customers' traffic patterns throughout their online sessions, including which pages or specific URLs a customer views while using the Site. Moen may gather this information directly or by employing third party marketing and database management service providers.  Moen participates in the Adobe Marketing Cloud Identity Cooperative to better understand how you use our website and apps across the various devices you use, and to deliver tailored promotions. Learn more about how Adobe does this.

#### Personal Information (You Actively Provide)

If you provide information about yourself by registering on a page, ordering a product, filling out a survey, entering a promotion (including contests, sweepstakes, offers and rebates) or otherwise voluntarily telling us or our business partners information that specifically identifies you, we will collect and use that Personal Information to respond to your request, and for other business purposes, including identifying customer preferences and improving our products and services and the content of this Site or other Interfaces. This information may be disclosed to our staff and to third parties involved in the completion of your transaction, the delivery of your order or the analysis and support of your use of the Site.

Please note that if you provide an email address and chose to access the Site through links we send to that email account, Moen and its contractors may collect personally identifiable information about your behavior, including purchasing behavior, time spent on the Site or other Interfaces, and any downloaded materials. This information will only be used by Moen and its affiliates and will not be sold to any third party. We may also contact you by email, regular mail, fax, text message, or telephone from time to time with information about our new products and services, special offers, upcoming events and changes to this Site or other Interfaces. If you do not wish to be contacted by all or any of these methods, you may let us know by sending an email message to us at webmaster@moen.com. Please be sure to give us your exact name and address, and your detailed request so we can respond appropriately.

#### How To Access Or Modify Your Personal Information

You have the right to access and modify your Personal Information. If you have registered with the Site, you can access or modify your stored Personal Information by accessing the "My Account" area of the Site, or you can access and change your Personal Information by contacting us at webmaster@moen.com.  Moen will endeavor to update your information within 10 business days.  If your information is not promptly updated, please be sure to contact us again to let us know.

#### Sharing Information

Anonymous Information – By using this Site or our other Interfaces, you are consenting that we may share your Anonymous Information with third parties including our affiliates and business partners to improve our product offerings, our marketing, our Sites and Interfaces and otherwise to better serve our customers as described in this Privacy Policy.  For example, we have arranged with third party providers to help us with marketing services and information gathering. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Site, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to this and other websites to target information for goods and services. This Anonymous Information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is industry standard technology used by many major web sites. No personally identifiable information is collected or used in this process. They do not know the name, phone number, address, email address, or credit card details about the user.

Personal Information – By providing Moen with your Personal Information, you are consenting to certain uses of that information.  We use your Personal Information to fulfill your order and provide services and improved experiences to you but, unless you consent otherwise, we will only share your Personal Information with third parties under contract to us as necessary to service you as explained below. We employ companies to perform certain functions on our behalf, such as fulfilling orders, delivering packages, remarketing services and services related to the design, maintenance and improvement of this Site, our customer and marketing databases and other Interfaces. Some of these companies may have access to your Personal Information as part of their contract with us. For example, we have arranged with Paymetric to process your credit card information. They use SSL encryption of your credit card information. You may access the Paymetric website (www.paymetric.com) and privacy policy to read more about the security measures they employ.

If you provide us with your additional consent, we may share your Personal Information with business partners with whom we have joint marketing arrangements. For example, at the time that you provide us with your contact information or other Personal Information, we may also give you the opportunity to have your Personal Information shared with other third parties or posted on this Site for reasons we will describe at the time we make the request. If you later change your mind and no longer want us to share your Personal Information with our marketing affiliates and business partners, then please let us know by contacting us at webmaster@moen.com.

All Information - Regardless of whether you have provided us with consent, we expressly reserve the right and will share all your information (both Personal Information and Anonymous Information) as we deem necessary to comply with applicable laws, police investigations, or in legal proceedings where disclosure of such information is relevant and permitted by law. Moen Incorporated will also assign, sell, license, or otherwise transfer to a third party all information in its databases in connection with an assignment, sale, joint venture, or other transfer or disposition of a portion or all of Moen’s services, or the assets, business or stock of Moen Incorporated.

#### Links To Other Websites

On this Site, we may provide as a convenience to you links to other websites, including sites operated by us, our partners, associates, or independent third parties. These links are provided as a convenience to you. Each website has its own privacy practices, as described in that site's privacy policy. Those practices may be different than the practices described herein, and we urge you to read each website's privacy policy carefully before you use or submit information to that site. Additionally, to the extent that you follow a link to a website operated by an independent third party, please be aware that we exercise no authority or control over that third party, and cannot and are not responsible for any information that you may submit at that site.

#### Where Do We Store And How Do We Secure Your Personal Information

Your Personal Information will be kept in a database held on servers kept in a physically and technologically secure environments located in Kansas, Ohio, Texas, and Utah accessed only by authorized personnel or contractors who are required to keep your information confidential. All transmissions of your credit card information are encrypted. We also have in place internal procedures to confirm general company compliance with this Policy.  
Your information will be transferred to Moen Incorporated, located in the State of Ohio, United States of America, which location may be outside of your own country, and by providing us with your information, you are consenting to such transfer. Although we will use all reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of any Personal Information collected, we will not be liable for disclosure of Personal Information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized acts of third parties.

#### Important Note To Kids (and Parents)

We do not wish to obtain Personal Information from children under 16 who are using our Site unsupervised. Before providing us your name, address, e-mail address, credit card details or any other personal information, be sure to ask your parents or guardian for permission.   

PARENTS:  To our knowledge, we do not collect Personal Information online from children under 16. If you are a parent or guardian and think we have information about your child, please email us at webmaster@moen.com.  To learn more about how to protect your child online, visit the FTC's www.OnGuardOnline.gov.

#### User Name And Password

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your user name and password. You are also responsible for all uses of your membership, whether or not authorized by you. You agree to immediately notify Moen Incorporated of any unauthorized use of your user name or password.

#### Cookies

Like many other commercial sites, we may utilize a standard technology called a "cookie" to collect information about how our site is used. A cookie is a small data text file, which a website stores on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to us. Cookies were designed to help a website recognize a user's browser as a previous visitor and thus save and remember any preferences that may have been set while the user was browsing the site. Cookies can track that you are authenticated to the Site, personalize home pages, identify which parts of a site have been visited or keep track of selections, such as those selected in a "shopping cart." Our cookies may collect your domain name and track your selections through our site. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on a computer virus, or capture your e-mail address. The cookies make your use of the Site easier, make the Site run more smoothly and help us to maintain a secure Site.

To make a purchase at the Moen Online Store you need to have all cookies enabled. We use cookies in connection with purchases to keep track of what you have in your basket and to remember you when you return to our stores. Cookies cannot harm your computer and do not contain any personal or private information. For information about how to disable cookies, please consult your web browser's help menu.

**Questions or Concerns About Your Information; How to Contact Us**

If you need information or have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our use of your Personal Information, or wish to review all of your Personal Information, you may contact our Manager, Digital Experience Marketing via e-mail at webmaster@moen.com, or via mail at Moen Incorporated, Website Privacy, 25300 Al Moen Drive North Olmsted, OH 44070, or via telephone at 1-800-BUY-MOEN.

In order to facilitate the transfer of data between the US and EU countries, the US and the EU have entered into a "safe harbor program," under which data can be transferred from the EU to participating non-EU companies. The program has a set of seven principles, to which Moen complies with respect to the data collected and used as described in this Privacy Policy. As part of that program, while we strive to respond to your concerns, we recognize that we may not always answer all of your questions, and as such if you are an EU resident, we will participate with the Data Protection Authority in the country in which you reside. Thus to the extent that you feel that your questions have not been answered, and you are a resident of an EU Member country, you should feel free to contact the Data Protection Authority of the country in which you reside.

**Updates to Our Policy**

From time to time we may change our Privacy Policy. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting an updated copy on this Site. Please check this Site periodically for updates.

**This policy is effective as of January 2010  
Last update:  June 2019**

http://www.moen.com/legal-notice

Moen Incorporated  
25300 Al Moen Drive  
North Olmsted OH 44070
